Is Haowen really hurt?
浩文受伤了
Yes.
是啊
This morning, you know,
你说今天早上
[when I got to his home,]
我一到他家呀
[I found that]
我就发现那浩文啊
he was almost lying on the floor.
都快躺到地下了
There was a big bump
那头上啊
on his head,
这么大个包啊
bruised and swollen,
又青又紫的
and even some blood was coming out.
都渗出血来了
As a mother,
你说我这当妈的
how could I not worry about it?
看了能不心疼吗
I just want to ask Xin
你说我就想问问心心
what's going on with them?
这到底是咋回事啊
[Why did]
这两口子
[they have a fight?]
怎么还动上手了呢
[Mrs. Xu]
亲家母啊
[I've seen that]
我这也看过了
[your house is quiet]
你这房子挺宽敞
[spacious.]
挺大的
[Why not let Xin]
要不 就让心心
[stay with you for a while.]
在娘家多住一段时间吧
I'll have the nanny
回头我让保姆
bring Xin's things
把心心的东西
back here.
给她运回来
What's your opinion?
你看行不
She's been in a bad mood these days,
你说现在心心这脾气大
which swings a lot.
情绪不稳定
If they fight again,
你说万一再动起手来
I do feel hurt
你说伤着浩文吧
if Haowen gets hurt.
我也心疼
If Xin gets hurt,
你说要是伤着心心了
that would hurt
那可是伤的
not just her,
不是一个人哪
it would hurt the baby, too.
那伤的就俩人哪
The consequences
你说这后果
are unimaginable.
真是不堪设想
I think it's better to
我想啊
have Xin stay with you
就叫心心在娘家住着吧
for as long as she wants.
想住多久就住多久
What do you think?
你说呢
Mom.
妈
Xin, you get up.
心心 你起来了
I finally get to sleep in.
我也是难得睡个懒觉
I heard you talking outside,
一听您在外头说话呢
so I get up quickly.
我可不得赶紧起来
I'm already an adult
我也这么大人了
and pregnant
你说肚子里啊
with my second child.
二胎都怀上了
How can't I decide
怎么我想住哪儿
where I want to stay
住多久
and for how long?
我自己还做不了主了呢
Xin
心心
You can decide
你能做得了主
to stay wherever you want.
你愿意住哪儿就住哪儿
For a young couple,
你说小两口
it's normal to argue from time to time.
吵架就吵架嘛
But why do you have to hit him?
你干吗要动手啊
When did I ever hit him?
我什么时候动手了
I didn't hit him.
我没动手啊
On Haowen's head,
这浩文头上
there's such a big bump,
这么一个大个包啊
bruised and bleeding.
又青又紫都渗血
Wasn't that you?
那不是你打的吗
I just don't understand.
你说我就想不明白了
Way back in the day,
你说以前
you two started from scratch.
你们两个白手起家
Together, you
共同在那儿
worked hard to build your business.
艰苦奋斗创业
You've been through tough times.
你啥苦日子没过过来啊
But I never saw you fight.
也没见你俩吵架呀
Now that life is better,
你说现在日子好了
and you are living in such a big house.
房子这么大地住着
You have everything you want.
要啥有啥
Why are you starting causing trouble?
你怎么还作上了呢
You're not just making trouble,
你不仅你作
you even hit Haowen.
你还动手打人了
This is between
这是我和贾浩文
Jia Haowen and me.
两个人的事情
Mom, please leave us alone, okay?
妈 您就别管了 行吗
How can I do nothing?
我能不管吗
When I entered the home,
你说我一进家门
I saw the home
看到那个家里
was totally a mess.
都弄得鸡飞狗跳的
Xiongxiong told me
那熊熊跟我说
you two were getting divorced.
你俩要离婚了
He's not even going to school.
他连学都不上了
Who told you that?
谁跟你学的呀
It's Jia Haowen, right?
贾浩文跟你学的 是吧
He told you I made the home
说我把家里
into chaos
弄得鸡飞狗跳的
and I hit his head
说我给他脑袋上
and gave him a big
打一大包
bleeding bump.
往外渗血
That's what he said, right?
是他说的是吧
Just ask him to come here
你让他来 来
and clear this up
当着我的面
in front of me.
大家说说清楚
Did I really hit him?
我打他了吗
Did I even touch him?
我动他一根手指了吗
As a grown man,
他多大人了
he's still telling mommy on me.
还跟妈告状呢
He wants a divorce, right?
他要离婚是吧
Okay!
离
Fine, then divorce.
离就离
You see,
亲家母
look at Xin's temper.
你看心心这脾气
Yes, yes.
是 是
Well.
那个
She's pregnant, so her temper is bad.
怀孕了 脾气不好
Please
亲家母
don't be angry.
你 你别生气啊
That's just angry words.
她说气话呢
They won't divorce, they won't.
不能离 不能离
Here, have some water.
你快 喝口水
Alright, alright.
好 好
Please, calm down.
姐 消消气啊
Okay.
行
Mrs. Jia
亲家母
You hardly ever come here.
你好不容易来一趟
I thought about it.
我想了想啊
We will not cook at home.
咱不在家里做了
[Why don't we go out for a walk?]
我领你出去逛一逛
Let's go eat outside.
咱上饭店吃去
Yes.
是
Let us hang out.
我陪你出去转转
[Mrs. Jia]
亲家母
[After we cross this bridge,]
一会儿咱们过这个桥
[we'll show you that tower.]
我领你看看那个塔去
See?
看见没有
That tower.
那个塔
It's said to be hundreds of years old.
据说有好几百年了
I'm telling you.
我跟你说
It's a real antique.
那还是一个古董呢
After that, we'll come back to
完了咱们回来以后啊
this street, it is full of restaurants.
这趟街咱们全是饭店
You pick one.
你挑一个
They have Northeastern Chinese cuisine,
这有什么东北菜
Shanghai cuisine,
有什么本帮菜
and Cantonese cuisine.
有什么广东菜
It's said that this restaurant
他们说这
is quite good.
这家做得挺好的
We'll have
你想吃啥
whatever you want.
咱们就吃啥
Right.
对
But my family...
但是我家
Haowen
浩文
I see you.
我看见你了
[Over here.]
这儿呢 这儿呢
[Come over here.]
你过来
Go
去
Come here.
过来 过来
get a few boat tickets.
买几张船票
Over here.
过来
Mom.
妈
Dad.
爸
What a nice surprise!
你们怎么都在这儿啊
I can show you around if you want.
出来玩让我带你们去
Put your hand down.
手拿下来
Put it down.
我挠痒痒 妈
Scratching what?
挠什么痒
You just put it down.
你给我拿下来你
Mr. and
亲家
[Mrs. Xu]
亲家母
[please look at this.]
你们看看
[They just had a small fight]
小两口吵架
[and he ended up being hit like this.]
就被打成这个样子
Mom, who hit me?
妈 谁打我了
I was getting something for Xin
我给心心拿东西
from the top of the cabinet,
柜子上面
and a box fell down
掉下来个箱子
and hit me.
砸了一下
Stop making things up.
你可别给我编了你
Mom.
妈
I got you boat tickets, let's go.
我买了船票 咱玩去啊
I'll be the guide.
我当导游
Let's go.
走走走
What box? It's nonsense.
什么磕啊 你别编了
Mom, you...
妈 你
Let's get on the boat.
上船吧
Let's go.
咱们上船啊
Here, you take this.
这你拿着
It's OK. I have money with me.
不是 我带着钱呢
My mom's here,
我妈不在这儿吗
and you may take the bill.
您请客买单
Haowen
浩文啊
Tell me the truth.
你跟爸说句老实话
What really happened with your head?
这到底是怎么弄的
It's an accident,
磕的
Alright, Mom, look at me.
好嘞 妈 来
No matter what Mrs. Jia says,
不管亲家母 说啥
just be nice to her.
你都笑脸相迎
Of course.
那肯定
Don't forget it.
记着啊
That's great, Mom.
好嘞 妈
Mom, look. How beautiful the scenery is.
妈 你看那景多美啊
Cheer up!
高兴点啊
Dad, come here.
爸 来来来
Mom.
妈
Let me take a picture for you.
给你们照个相
The scenery is really beautiful.
这景可漂亮了
Come on.
来
One, two, three.
一 二 三
You can make a heart shape, Dad
来 比个心 爸
and Mom.
妈
Show me a heart, Mom.
比个心 妈
Left hand.
左手
Okay, show me a heart.
来 比心
Haowen
浩文
Are we getting off the boat later?
一会儿咱下船吗
Yes, Dad. It's so beautiful
下 爸
that we should take a good look around.
景可美了 好好转转
Mrs. Xu
亲家母
Mom
妈
[Let me tell you...]
我跟你说
Look.
看
How beautiful the scenery is.
景色多么的秀丽
[Look at the mountains and rivers.]
山川 河流
[Come.]
来
[Let me take a picture for you.]
妈 我给您照张相
[Cheer up.]
开心点
[My wonderful mom.]
我烛光里的妈
Aren't you happy, Mom?
高兴吧 妈
It's alright, Mom.
没事 妈
How nice this is.
多好啊
Look at there,
你看
[Mom.]
妈
[We're having fun, please cheer up.]
您这出来玩 高兴点
[Don't keep a long face.]
老拉着个脸
Haowen
儿子
Don't look back.
别回头
[I noticed that you are more and more]
我发现你对你岳父岳母
Look ahead.
往前看
[attentive to your in-laws.]
是越来越殷勤
You keep calling them Dad
你说你一口一个爸
and Mom
一个妈
so affectionately.
叫那个亲热啊
Do you ever notice me,
你眼里还有没有
your real mom?
我这个亲妈呀
You keep saying "real mom" yourself.
您自己都亲妈亲妈
Aren't we on the same side?
难道咱俩还不一头的呀
Don't look back.
别回头了
[Are you jealous of this?]
这还吃醋呢
[Do you really want me to]
我当着岳父说
call you "my real mom"
戴个帽
in front of my in-laws?
亲妈 亲妈
How ridiculous.
累不累啊
Now I finally understand
我现在总算知道了
why you've spoiled Xin
你为啥把心心
to be like this.
惯成这个样子
When it comes to your in-laws,
你在你岳父岳母家
you have no bottom line at all.
一点底线都没有啊
Mom, don't get involved in our matters.
妈 我俩的事您别掺和
We are doing fine on our own.
本来我们自个儿好好的
You'll only make it messier.
您越掺和越乱
With Xin being like this,
那心心这个样子
how can you lead a happy life.
怎么跟你过日子
How can I not get involved?
我怎么能不掺和
How can I turn a blind eye to you?
我能不管吗
Let me tell you.
我告诉你啊
I've found that your father-in-law
我发现你岳父这个人啊
is a reasonable person.
是个明事理的人
Today,
我今天
I must have a good talk with him.
一定要找他好好谈谈
Alright, Mom.
行 妈
Just stop meddling.
别管了啊
I can handle my own affairs.
我自己的事
I can manage, don't worry about it.
能处理好 您就放心啊
Dad, come on.
爸 来来来
Let's take a picture.
我给咱们拍照
Come.
来
Okay, I'll take a picture for moms first.
好好好 先给俩妈照
Watch your back.
看着点后边
Alright.
好嘞
Look at me.
来
Let me get the
我把这个带上
plaque in the picture.
这个名字啊
One, two, three.
来 一二三
Dad, just join them.
爸 您也来
Alright.
好
Come here.
来
[There are more good dishes coming.]
后面还有好菜呢
Take your time eating.
慢慢吃啊
There are also two new dishes today.
今儿还有俩新菜呢
Dad, I've got everything arranged,
爸 您说我都安排完了
and you paid the bill.
你说 把单还给买了
My Dad is helping me save money.
让我省钱呢 我爸
Uh, Dad, Mom,
那个 爸 妈
the company is pressing me.
这公司紧着催呢
I have to go to a meeting.
我还得去开个会啊
The food is all arranged.
饭菜都安排好了
Just take your time.
你们慢慢吃
Dad,
爸
Mom,
妈
my mom's temper
我妈这脾气啊
is so much better now.
现在可好了
Thank you for your patience.
多担待
[Mom,]
妈
let's talk at home later.
有话咱回家说
Your temper is much better now, right?
你现在脾气可好了
I knew it.
我知道
I'm leaving.
我走了
Haowen
儿子
Does it hurt?
疼不
It's fine, Mom.
没事 没事 妈
Haowen
浩文 浩文
Take this with you.
来来 把这拿着
Mom, look.
妈 你看
Dad really cares about me.
我爸多疼我
Mom,
妈
I'm leaving now.
走了啊
Take your time eating.
慢慢吃着 您
Be careful with your wound.
你小心你那伤口啊
I'll be fine.
放心吧
Mrs. Jia
亲家母
Look.
你看
This is the fish you love.
这是你爱吃的鱼
This is the beef you love.
你爱吃的牛肉
This is the shrimp you love.
你爱吃的虾
This is the chicken you love.
你爱吃的鸡
I'll get it for you.
来来 来
Have some soup first.
你先喝点汤
Here you are.
来
Try it.
尝尝
Mr. and Mrs. Xu
亲家
I really didn't want to say this.
我本来是不想说的
You prepared
你说你们准备了
such a sumptuous feast for me.
这么一桌丰盛的宴席
As in-laws of each other,
咱家和和睦睦的
we should get along harmoniously.
咱们亲家母三个人
I thought we can chat together.
一起唠唠嗑
I was planning to come here to take care
我从老家来
of Xin during her postpartum period.
我是照顾心心月子来的
When I walked in their house,
我一进门
I saw a huge bump on my son's head
就发现我儿子这个头上
that was this big.
这么大的包
Mrs. Jia
亲家母
It was this big.
这么大
You didn't see it earlier,
你刚才没看见呢
when I got home, it was this large,
我一回家这么大
both purple and red.
又紫又红
And it was oozing blood.
渗出血来了
Xiongxiong also told me
你说这熊熊跟我说
that his parents are getting divorced.
我爸妈要离婚了
[That can't be true.]
那不能
When I heard that,
我这一听啊
I was over-anxious,
我这火啊
and my anger just rose up.
就这么上来了
Mrs. Xu
亲家母啊
We are women.
咱们都是当女人的
We should understand each other.
咱都互相理解
Haowen's father passed away early.
浩文他爸呀 走得早
It's just my son and me.
就是我跟儿子两个
We rely on each other.
相依为命
It wasn't easy raising him.
我把他拉扯大 不容易
Yes, right.
是 是
I never
我从小就没有
laid a finger on him.
碰过他一个手指头
Haowen has turned out very well.
浩文这孩子 很争气
He's been so good, growing up like this.
乖乖的啊 长了这么大
And then he started
然后又开了
such a big company.
这么大一公司
He brought Xin into the family.
把心心娶到家
Their marriage is perfect.
夫妻美满
As a mother and mother-in-law,
我觉得我这个当婆婆
I think
当妈的
I've done my duty.
我尽到责任了
Every man cares about their pride,
男人都是要脸的
right?
是不是
When he goes out
你说出了门
with a bump this big on his head,
这头上这么大个包
how is that man supposed
你让那男人
to face people?
这个脸往哪儿放
Besides,
你还有了
I think their marriage
你说我感觉他们两口子
is very good.
真的是小日子很美满
Yes.
是
Haowen is so
你说他对心心
devoted to Xin.
宠得不得了
Yes, he is.
对 对
He gives her whatever she wants.
心心要啥给啥
When she wanted a house, he bought it.
要房买房
When she wanted a car, he bought it.
要车买车
And she got her bags, too.
要包买包
As for the expansion of your house,
包括你们家的扩建
Haowen also contributed to it,
那也是浩文出了力的
right?
是不是
Yes.
是是
He's been a great son-in-law
你说你这样的个女婿
and a perfect husband.
这样一个老公
What else can you ask from him?
上哪儿找去
We can always talk about any issues.
有啥话说话
Why resort to violence, right?
你说 干吗要动手啊
As a mother,
我这当妈的
it breaks my heart to see that.
看了我这心疼啊
Any couples
夫妻吵架
will have disagreements.
这个没有不拌嘴的
It's a normal part of life, right?
这都是正常事 对吧
Besides, she even asks for a divorce
再说了 提出离婚
while she is pregnant
你现在自己身子
with the second child.
怀着老二呢
If they do get divorced,
离了婚
the baby will be born without a father.
那孩子生出来就没爸爸
What will she do then?
你这怎么办哪
Am I right?
你说是不是
We can't let them
这不能让他们
reach that point.
走到这一步啊
Of course no.
不能
Rest assured, it won't happen.
你放心 不能
Well.
你说
Mrs. Xu,
亲家母啊
have you and Mr. Xu
你跟亲家
ever argued before?
是不也吵过架啊
When you were arguing,
你们吵架的时候
did you dare to hit him?
你敢打他吗
Yes.
敢
If I hit you,
我打你
would you dare to hit back?
你敢回手吗
No.
不敢
Mrs. Jia
亲家母
Please calm down.
消消气
Divorce is not something
离婚这种事情
that will happen in our family.
不会发生在我们老许家
[Right.]
对
It's not our family tradition.
这不是我们家的传统
Don't worry about it.
你放心
You two
你们老两口啊
are reasonable people.
是明事理的人
[That's why I'm here to ask you]
所以我来跟你们说
to prevent Xin
阻止心心
from taking this step.
不能走这一步啊
Right?
是不是
She will never take that step.
坚决走不到这一步
Don't worry.
你放心
[Yes.]
对啊
[Mrs. Jia,]
亲家母
[drink some soup, it's getting cold.]
你 快喝点汤 凉了
[Don't worry.]
放心
[Look,]
你看这个
[the area of this apartment complex]
小区的占地面积
[is quite large.]
还是挺大的
[The landscaping is wonderful.]
这绿化真的不错
We just crossed this bridge
我们刚才从这个桥
earlier.
过去的嘛
This bridge, right?
就这条桥是吧
Yes, that one.
对对对 对
How is it?
怎么样
We've got plenty of video and photos.
视频和图片拍了不少
The material is sufficient.
素材足够用了
Great.
好
Director Sun
孙主任
[How about]
怎么样
our best sales manager?
我们这个名牌销售经理
How was the introduction?
介绍得怎么样 给你
She's so professional
太专业了
that I almost wanted to buy it.
忽悠得我都想买了
I just had them go on-site
刚才我让他们去实景
to take some footage.
拍了一些素材
We have both photos and videos.
图片视频都有
We will arrange them when we get back
回去我们细化一下
and give you the plan as soon as possible.
尽快把方案给到您
Wanzhen is particularly excellent.
婉真特别优秀啊
Thank you for recommending us
谢谢您给我们推荐
such a talented person.
这么好的人才
I appreciate your insight.
还是要感谢您多关照呢
Wanzhen,
婉真
accompany Ms. Xu for us.
多陪陪许总
Okay.
好嘞
[You two can continue.]
你们俩聊
[Okay.]
好吧
Alright.
好
Okay then.
好嘞
I'll go back to work now.
我先忙去了
Okay, you go about your work.
好嘞 您忙您的
Keep it up!
加油啊
[What do you say?]
怎么样
[I didn't expect such great benefits.]
没想到还有这福利啊
[You don't know.]
你都不知道
[When it's lunchtime]
我现在一到
[every day,]
中午吃饭的时候
I have to escape from the company.
就得往外躲
The smell of takeout all over the office
那满公司外卖那味
makes me feel nauseous.
闻着我就恶心
I just can't stand it.
根本受不了
If I had known you were coming,
早知道你要来
I would have made more.
我就多做一些
It is already enough.
够了 够了 够了
Message.
手机
[One, two, three.]
一 二 三
[Nice.]
漂亮
[Good.]
好
They are having quite a good time.
玩得还挺好
So happy.
挺开心
What's that?
什么呀
A video from the nanny
保姆发来的视频
with Wanzhen and Zhenzhen
就婉婉 真真
playing in the park.
在那儿玩呢
Did you hire a male nanny?
你找了个男保姆啊
What male nanny?
什么男保姆啊
It's sent by the female nanny.
阿姨发来的
[One, two, three.]
一 二 三
You still don't believe me?
你还不信了你
Just look.
你看看看
[Great!]
好
This young man looks quite good.
你看这小伙子挺精神啊
Who is he?
干吗的
He's just a
就是一个
neighbor.
邻居
You hesitated.
你犹豫了
I...
我
Me and my neighbor have lived
我跟我们家邻居
across the hall for over ten years.
对门住了十几年
And we haven't been this close.
也没玩得这么好啊
Tell me the truth.
你说实话
Who is he?
到底干吗的
What are you thinking?
想什么呢
He's just Wanwan and Zhenzhen's
他就是婉婉 真真的
pediatrician.
儿科医生
He's currently
他现在跟孩子
a very good friend of the kids.
玩得可好了
He's closer to them than to me.
比跟我熟
So you've got another doctor, too?
又换医生了
What do you mean?
你到底想说什么啊
He is your neighbor
你邻居
and your kids' pediatrician.
孩子的医生
I think this young man
我觉得这个小伙子啊
has a clear plan, which may be
思路很清晰啊
achieving his goals indirectly, isn't he?
他是不是要曲线救国呀
Was he, from time to time,
是不是没事
delivering medicine to the kids
给孩子送送药
and showing you some kindness?
给你送送温暖啊
Just tell me yes or no.
你就说有没有
No.
没有
Really.
真的没有
Stop talking nonsense like this.
你这小话就别递了
It's really not going to happen.
真没戏
He's not suitable for me.
不合适
Why isn't he suitable?
怎么不合适啊
I think you two make a great couple.
我看着郎才女貌呀
You have a strong couple vibe.
情侣感很有的呀
You know, married women
你知道吧 已婚妇女啊
love to indulge in these sweet fantasies.
就喜欢磕糖
Come on,
快快快
tell me more.
给我扒一扒
I'll help you analyze it.
我帮你分析分析
I see that you don't mean to analyze
我看你啊 不是想分析
but to gossip.
就想扒
Well, I actually do want
那我还是真是挺想
to help you analyze.
帮你分析的
Look,
你看啊
we are all adults.
大家都是成年人了
We are all busy with
谁不上个班啊
our own work.
都挺忙的
There isn't much time
哪有那么多时间
to help take care of someone else's kids.
还帮你带孩子啊
Am I right?
是不是
It's not an obligation.
又不是义务的
I think this young man is
我觉得这个小伙子
definitely into you.
对你绝对有意图
Right now,
我现在啊
I don't want to think about these things.
不想想这些
I just want to focus on my work,
就想好好工作
making money and raising the kids.
好好赚钱 养孩子
Are you feeling insecure?
你是不是不自信了
Wanzhen, you can't be like this.
婉真 咱不能这样的
Even though you're divorced
虽然你离了婚
with two kids,
带着两个孩子
you can still
但是还是可以
start a new chapter.
开启第二春的
Many people find happiness
那很多人二婚以后
in their second marriage.
也是很幸福的呀
Don't be afraid, okay?
你不要怕 好吗
Are you going to eat or not?
你还吃不吃啊
If not, I'll take it away.
不吃我就收了
I do, I'll eat then.
我这 吃吃吃 吃
How about asking him out someday
要不哪天你把他约出来
and we have a meal together?
一起吃个饭
I'll help you figure it out.
我帮你断断
Okay.
行
Let's figure it out
帮你断断
and see if you need some help.
看你有没有病
This young man
这小伙子
definitely wants something.
肯定有想法
Don't doubt it, okay?
别不信好吗
Just eat your food.
你吃你的吧
Eating won't stop you talking.
吃还堵不上你嘴
I'm just having some fun.
乐趣嘛
You're really gossipy.
真八卦 你啊
The HR Department's comprehensive
人事部门综合考量
evaluation suggests Mu is the perfect man
阿木是最合适副总监
for the Deputy Director position.
这个位置的人选了
You see,
您看
his educational background
他的学历背景啊
and project experience
项目履历啊
are qualified for the position.
完全是可以胜任的
Moreover,
再一个
he is someone
他是咱们自己
we have trained ourselves.
培养出来的
As a veteran of our Content Department,
又是内容部的元老了
promotion of him will
推他上来
encourage more young people
可以鼓励更多的年轻人
and show them the advancement
也让他们知道
opportunities in our company
咱们公司的上升渠道
are totally available.
是开放的
What do you think, Mr. Zhang?
您说呢 张总
Mu is indeed competent,
那阿木合适倒是合适
but he might be too suitable.
就是有点太合适了
Do you know
你知道
why I have been wanting to
我为什么
hire someone from outside?
一直想在外面招人吗
"A monk from outside reads sutras better."
外来的和尚好念经
This old saying truly
这句老话啊
makes sense.
还是有道理的
Our company
我们新苗公司呢
urgently needs to expand
现在急需要
some new business areas.
拓展新的业务
So we need to hire from outside
所以你就得从外面请人
because they can
因为他们
bring new resources
可以带来新的资源
and fresh perspectives.
新的视野
[This is something Xinmiao urgently needs.]
这个是我们新苗急需的
Let's start with external hiring.
先招着吧
If we really can't find anyone suitable,
实在招不着
we can promote from within.
我们再内部提拔
Do you have any other matters?
你还有事吗
No, nothing else.
没事
Mr. Wu
吴总
[This plan]
这个方案
[should be quite easy to execute, right?]
应该挺好做的吧
The plan is easy, but making money is not.
方案好做 钱难挣
Mu,
阿木啊
take a break for now,
你们先休整一下
then let's have a meeting together
然后咱们一起开个会
to finalize the plan.
把方案做出来
We'll submit it to Mr. Zhang
五点之前
before 5 o'clock.
交给张总
Okay.
好
Your expression is a bit serious.
表情有点严肃啊
Here's a new situation.
新情况
I just talked to Mr. Zhang
我刚才去找老张
about Mu's promotion.
说阿木升职的事
Guess what he said.
你猜他怎么说
He doesn't want to promote Mu.
他不想升阿木
Did he tell you why?
说为什么了吗
He still wants to hire from outside,
还是想从外面找
find the person bringing new resources.
觉得能带来资源
If that fails,
实在不行
then we'll promote one from within.
再从内部升
Bringing up Mu's promotion with him
之前跟他提阿木的事
earlier was indeed a bit rash.
确实有点冒进了
Anyway, I think
反正我觉得
he is determined
他是下定决心
to hire someone from outside.
要从外面找了
If it really happens,
这个人要是真的来
the person will be a big threat to you.
那对你威胁可就大了
When do you plan to tell him
你打算什么时候跟他说
about your pregnancy?
你怀孕的事
I need to wait a bit longer.
再等等吧
I'm still in the first trimester.
我这还保着胎呢
What I want to tell you
我要跟你说的
is about this.
就是这个事
You absolutely cannot mention
现在绝对不能说
your pregnancy right now.
你怀孕的事
He is a person
他这个人
with a lot of thoughts and worries.
想法多 心思重
I'm afraid that if you tell him,
我怕你说了
he'll overthink things even more.
他想得更多
Wanzhen
婉真
There's a dinner party tonight.
晚上有个饭局
You'll come with me.
你跟我一起去啊
Mr. Qian
钱总
You can take me with you.
您可以叫我去啊
I can even help you with the drinks.
我还能给你挡酒呢
Next time when there are
你等下回
high-end clients, I'll take you.
有高端客户一定带你去
Mr. Qian
钱总
Then can I skip this one?
那我就不去了吧
Feifei can drink, let her handle it.
菲菲能喝 让她喝
No, you have to go.
不是 你得去啊
Director Xu
那个许总监
is your friend, isn't she?
不是你朋友吗
Will she be there, too?
许总监也去啊
Yes, we'll have dinner and chat.
是啊 咱们边吃边聊
And you need to discuss with her
而且那个营销方案
about the marketing plan
还得你跟她碰呢
If you really can't make it,
你要实在不行
I'll send Director Sun instead.
我让孙主任去对了
No, no, no.
不不不
I have to go.
我得去啊
I made this marketing plan,
这营销策划是我做的
so I must be there.
我必须得到
I'll go.
我去
Great.
好
Then get ready.
那你收拾一下
Wanzhen
婉真姐
Can you drink?
你能喝酒吗
You should be careful about
那钱总的酒量
Mr. Qian's drinking capacity.
你要了解一下的
How is it going?
怎么样了
The project proposal is done.
项目书做好了
I'm about to deliver it to you.
正准备给您送去呢
Here is the contract.
这是合同
Perfect timing.
正好
Then
一会儿
let's go over it in the car.
我们俩在车上对对啊
We'd better sign the contract soon
赶紧把合同签了呀
to avoid any further complications.
省着夜长梦多呀
Let's go now.
走 跟我走
It's almost time to get off work.
快下班了
You're working overtime today.
你今天加班
I mean, the client is about to off duty.
我是说对方要下班了
Then you must hurry up.
所以你得快点啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
Side stitches.
岔气了
It's okay. I'm fine.
没事 没事
Hold this.
你拿着
Mr. Zhang
张总
Aren't we here to sign the contract?
咱不是来签合同吗
Who told you that the contract
谁告诉你吃饭
can't be signed during a meal?
不能签合同呢
We'll also have some drink.
还得喝酒呢
What?
什么
What did you think I asked you for?
你以为我叫你来干吗的
Mr. Zhang
张总
Wanzhen
婉真
Don't bother with this.
你就别忙活了
Let the waitstaff handle it.
让服务员弄吧
It's okay. It's part of my job.
没事 这是我分内的事
Okay.
好
Mr. Qian
钱总
There they are.
来了
Look.
你看
[Sorry.]
不好意思啊
[Mr. Zhang]
张总
[There was a bit of traffic on the way.]
路上有点堵车
You're just in time.
时间刚刚好
We just arrived as well.
我们也刚到
This must be Director Xu.
这位就是许总监吧
Mr. Qian, nice to meet you.
钱总 你好
I'm Xu Meng'an
许梦安
I've heard so much about you.
久仰大名啊
Likewise.
久仰 久仰
I've heard that
我可听说
Director Xu is a
许总监
formidable woman when drinking.
在酒桌上可是女中豪杰
Just empty praise.
江湖虚名
Well, today
那咱今儿
we'll definitely drink well.
肯定得好好喝点
[We're here to discuss about the contract.]
今天咱们是来谈合同的
[After we drink well,]
喝好了
we'll sign it right away.
咱们马上就签
Yes.
是是是
Come.
来
Please, sit down.
坐坐坐
Wanzhen
婉真
What's going on?
什么情况
Do we really have to drink?
必须得喝吗
Yes.
得喝
Definitely.
必须喝
Come on.
来
Sit down.
坐坐坐
Come over.
过来
[Mr. Qian]
钱总啊
[Come on.]
来
Let's toast to a successful partnership.
预祝我们合作愉快
Cheers, Mr. Zhang.
来 张总
Director Xu hasn't drunk yet.
这许总监也没喝啊
Drink it.
喝了
I think it's too easy.
我觉得它不配
Director Xu,
许总监
are you going to
这是要
drink the whole pot?
拎壶冲啊
Yes.
对
Mr. Zhang,
张总
today, for the contract,
今天为了合同
I'm really giving it my all.
我可是拼了啊
Mr. Qian,
钱总
today
我今天
I will drink until you're satisfied.
一定喝到你满意为止
I'll drink until you're willing
喝到你愿意
to sign the contract with Mr. Zhang.
跟我们张总签合同为止
Alright.
好吧
Wanzhen
婉真
Get the spirits ready for me.
把酒给我准备上啊
No problem.
没问题
I'll drink it all!
我干了
Good.
好 好好
Director Xu
这许总监
is indeed living up to her reputation.
果然名不虚传啊
[She is truly someone.]
真是女中豪杰
[A female hero.]
巾帼英雄啊
[Gentlemen,]
各位男士啊
[look, the lady is drinking like this,]
你看女士都喝成这样了
[we can't be left behind, right?]
咱男的也不能   啊
[Let's have a drink, too.]
来一个 来一个
[Alright.]
好
Mr. Qian,
钱总
the contract is here
合同在这儿
and the pen is here.
笔在这儿
I'll drink all of this.
我干了
Well, you... I...
不是 你这 我
See, she always rushes to do everything.
你看这 就是个急脾气
You see?
你看
If I don't sign it today, I guess
我今儿要不签
I won't be able to get out of here.
我这看是出不去了
Or I'll have one drink, too.
要不我陪一个得了
[Don't.]
别别别
I'll have one more.
我再来一个
I'll sign it.
我签
I'll sign it right now.
我签签签
That's enough.
别别别
[Sit down, please.]
坐坐坐
Yunjie
云阶
Why aren't you leaving yet?
怎么还不走
You go ahead.
你先走吧
Don't worry about me.
你别管我了
Okay.
好
You scared me to death.
吓死我了
Look at the clothes I bought today.
看我今天买的衣服
Aren't they nice?
好看吧
Sure.
好看
You're dressed up
你穿这么隆重
with a dog collar around your neck.
还带个狗项圈
What do you know?
你懂什么
[This is called a choker.]
这叫贴颈项链
[I don't know that.]
我不懂
What shall we eat?
吃什么呀
We can't get home too late.
不能回家太晚了啊
Let's go.
走
It definitely won't be too late.
肯定不会太晚的
I'll take you there.
我带你去
Take it slow.
你慢点
Isn't it cool?
帅不帅
A little bit cool.
有点帅吧
But their skill
但这技术
is not so good.
差点
I feel like
我怎么觉得
it's similar to the band we saw
跟咱们上次音乐节
at the music festival last time.
那乐队差不多啊
Far from it, okay?
差远了 好吗
Aren't they better looking?
不比那帅吗
My dad is much better looking than them.
我爸比他们帅多了
Besides,
而且
I prefer
我还是更喜欢
someone with real talent.
真正有实力的
They are not playing as well as I do.
弹得还没我好呢
You're just boasting.
你就吹吧
Ladies,
美女
mind if we make friends?
可以交个朋友吗
[Look at what I bought.]
看我买了啥
Here you are.
来来来
Have some milk tea.
喝奶茶 喝奶茶
Hand these to others.
分一下 分一下
Okay.
好好好
Thank you.
谢谢
Come on, bro.
来来 兄弟
Okay.
好
Here, Yunjie.
来 云阶
Here.
来
Thank you.
谢谢
Here you are, bro.
来来 兄弟
Okay.
好
Here.
给给 给给给
Yunjie
云阶
Together.
来
One, two, three, cheers for friendship.
一二三 友谊万岁
Cheers.
干杯
Uncle,
叔叔
here is an issue
我有个情况
that I need to report to you.
得汇报一下
Dad,
老爸
about what I did today,
今天这事
can we not tell Mom?
能不告诉老妈吗
No.
不行
We never hide anything from your mother.
凡事都不要瞒着你妈妈
It's a family rule.
这是我们家的规矩
Besides,
再说了
we've always told you
我们从小就跟你说
not to have food or drink
不要吃喝
from strangers.
陌生人给你的东西
You're a middle school student now.
你现在是个初中生了
How could you forget this?
怎么连这个都忘了
What if there's something bad
万一这饮料里边
in the drink?
放点什么呢
Right?
是不是
Luckily, Liu Siming
得亏刘思明今天
reported this to me in time.
及时地跟我汇报
Traitor.
叛徒
Don't call Liu Siming
你别说人家刘思明
a traitor.
叛徒啊
In this case,
这件事
Liu Siming did the right thing.
刘思明做得对
It's really worrying.
多让人担心啊
Today,
我们今天
we really didn't do anything.
真的什么都没干
He Lu wanted to comfort me,
何璐说要安抚我
so she took me out to relax.
带我出来散散心而已
Comfort you about what?
安抚你什么
She said
她说
with the second child,
有了老二
the first child is not favored anymore.
老大就不吃香了
Why did you stop, Dad?
走啊 老爸
[You're back.]
回来啦
Yeah, we're home.
回来了
Come back.
回来
You just leave your shoes like this?
你这鞋就这么放啊
[I'm sorry.]
对不起 对不起
Meng'an hasn't come back yet.
梦安还没回来
She said she'll have dinner outside today
她说今天在外面有饭局
and won't come back for dinner.
不回来吃饭了
How's it?
怎么样
Are you okay?
没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
It's nothing much.
这才哪儿到哪儿啊
Are you okay?
你没事吧
I'm definitely fine.
我肯定没事啊
Just drank a lot of cold water.
喝一肚子凉水
If it wasn't you today,
今天要不是你的话
I'd definitely be in trouble.
我肯定折这儿了
You could have had some water, too.
其实你也可以喝点假的
That won't do.
那不行
One of us has to drink
咱俩总得有一个
the real stuff
喝真的吧
so that they won't find out.
那万一发现了呢
Besides,
再说了
I need to be positive
我得在领导面前
in front of my boss.
表现表现啊
Do you really need that?
你还用得着这么表现吗
You must have known I was coming,
你肯定是知道我要来
so you came to help me with the drinking.
才过来帮我挡酒的
I can only
我也只能
help you with these
从这些
things within
力所能及的事情上
my capability.
帮帮你
But this can't go on.
但是这样下去不行啊
Today I am the client,
今天碰到的客户是我
what about tomorrow,
那明天呢
day after tomorrow,
后天呢
and the day after that?
大后天呢
Unless you take me with you
除非你每次喝酒
every time you drink.
都带上我
Will you come?
行吗
Of course, I will.
当然行啊
I'd definitely be willing to.
我当然愿意啊
But what if
那万一
I have a business trip someday?
我要是哪天出差呢
What about that?
对不对
This pregnancy issue
这怀孕的事啊
can't be hidden for too long.
瞒不了太久
You need to think carefully
你还得好好
about what to do next.
想想清楚怎么办
[You're back.]
回来了
[You must be tired.]
累了吧
Did you drink?
喝酒了
How dare you drink?
你怎么敢喝酒啊
Just kidding.
逗你呢
Wanzhen helped me out.
婉真都替我挡了
Then what about the smelling?
那 那为什么一身酒气
She kept giving me
她一直给我
a towel soaked in alcohol,
那个 倒了酒的毛巾
so I had to keep wiping it on me.
我就一直得擦
That's just going all out with the act.
那不做戏做全套嘛
I'm impressed by you guys.
服了你们
You're back.
回来了
Ms. Li
李阿姨
The kids are sleeping?
孩子睡了
Yes.
睡了
Sorry about
这不好意思啊
making you wait so late.
让你等这么晚
It's not easy to take care of
你一个人带孩子啊
the kids all by yourself.
也不容易
By the way,
对了
the kids
孩子们
did their homework with Dr. Yu
今天是和楼上的俞医生
from upstairs today.
一起做的作业
Did Dr. Yu come over today?
俞医生也来了
Wanwan and Zhenzhen
是婉婉和真真
ran into him downstairs
在楼下碰到他
and wouldn't let him leave.
不肯让他走
They played ball with him for a while
拉着他玩了一会儿球
and asked him to come over to do homework.
说让人家来家里写作业
Dr. Yu is really nice.
俞医生人挺好的
Yes, he's very caring.
是 挺热心的
I'm leaving now.
我走了啊
Okay.
好
Be careful on the way.
注意安全啊
Goodbye.
再见
The child is asleep, don't go in.
孩子睡了 别去
You'll wake her up.
把她闹醒了
It won't help.
说什么也都没用
She'll find you annoying.
还嫌你烦
But,
不是
how did you talk to her?
那你是怎么跟她谈的呀
I've talked it over.
我都谈好了
I've explained
都说了
the seriousness of the situation.
事情的严重性
She understood.
她知道了
She also made a commitment
她也表了态
that she won't drink
以后也不会再去喝
strangers' drinks in the future.
陌生人的饮料
Isn't that good?
不挺好吗
What else can you do?
要不然呢
What do you think is up
你说云阶这孩子
with Yunjie lately?
最近是怎么了
Why is she always
怎么老跟男孩
hanging out with boys?
一块儿混啊
Is it because the lack of fatherly love?
是不是你父爱没给够
Why is this on me?
你说我干什么呀
I'm also angry about it.
我还生气呢
It's those little brats
是那帮臭小子
who are interested in my daughter.
打我闺女的主意
Each one of them
那么一个一个的
is ugly as can be.
长得歪瓜裂枣的
They're even worse than Liu Siming.
还不如刘思明呢
Liu Siming isn't good enough, either.
刘思明也不行啊
Right, he isn't good, either.
对 刘思明也不行
Maybe
或许啊
it's just the restlessness of puberty.
这就是青春期的躁动
Then it's even more urgent to talk.
那这更得好好聊聊了
I need to go talk to her.
我得去
What's your rush?
你躁动什么
Take it easy.
你不要躁动啊
Puberty involves not just restlessness
青春期不仅要躁动
but also rebellion.
还有叛逆
Don't provoke her.
你不要激她
The more you provoke her,
你越是激她
the more she will go against you.
她越是跟你对着干
You need to go with the flow.
要顺着毛捋
Right?
是吧
Do you know
你知不知道
what she told me today?
今天她跟我说什么了
What did she say?
说什么
She said
她说
that He Lu took her out
是何璐带她出去的
to comfort her.
为了安抚她
She also said
她还说
from now on
从今以后
they're in the same boat.
我们就是同病相怜
With the second child coming,
有了老二
the first child will no longer be favored.
老大就不吃香了
Now you are pregnant.
你现在是不是怀了老二
How do you talk to her
你怎么跟她说
and in what stand?
以什么立场跟她说
Have you thought about it?
你考虑过没有
In the future,
以后啊
we need to pay more attention to Yunjie.
我们对云阶要注意一点
Do not let her feel
不要让她觉得
left out.
自己被冷落了
So you mean to ignore it?
那你的意思就是不管了
No.
管啊
Just be mindful.
注意一点
How?
怎么注意啊
Be careful with your words.
说话注意一点
It's about putting yourself in her shoes.
就是将心比心
Aren't you the eldest child in the family?
你是不是老大
Yes.
是啊
After Xin was born,
你们家有了心心之后
did you feel
你是不是心里面
a sense of neglect?
也感觉到了那种冷落
Absolutely.
太有了
Yes.
对呀
My parents spoiled Xin
那我爸我妈宠心心
in all respects.
宠得真是没边了
But I think I'm fine.
但是我觉得我没问题啊
I've gotten over it, haven't I?
我这不也过来了吗
I think my physical and mental states
我觉得我的身心
are much healthier than Xin's.
可是比心心健康多了吧
That's you.
那是你啊
How many people in the world are like you
全世界有几个像你这么
who are so mentally strong?
内心强大的
Anyway,
反正
we must be
我们家
fair and equal.
一定要一碗水端平
It can't be.
端不平
Why not?
怎么端不平
You're not one of us, you wouldn't know.
你不是老大你不知道
Let me tell you,
我跟你讲
from now on, as long as
以后只要
you point out any issues she has,
你说她什么问题
she'll feel
她就会觉得
it's because of the second child.
是因为有了老二
So,
所以
it's not what you think.
根本不是你想的那样
We must discipline her when it's needed.
该管的时候还得管
Don't worry too much
也不用顾虑她
about her feelings.
那么多的感受
Especially you, you know?
尤其是你 知道吗
Don't always make excuses for her.
别老给她找理由
You're such a tough mom.
你这个妈心真硬啊
You're the one who's too soft.
是你这个爸心太软
There's one more thing.
还有个事
Help me think about this.
你给我想想
About the pregnancy,
怀孕这事
it probably can't be hidden anymore.
估计是瞒不住了
How should I tell Mr. Zhang?
我得怎么跟张总说呀
Say it as it is.
该怎么说怎么说
There's nothing to hide.
没什么好隐瞒的
Just one child
你说一个孩子
has already made us
就已经让我们
exhausted.
心力交瘁了
Why do we have to go through
为什么那么想不开
this again by having the second one?
还要生个老二呢
Let's take it easy.
咱俩轻松点
Wouldn't it be better to live longer?
多活两年不好吗
No.
不好
It's better to have more kids in home.
家里还是热闹点好
Right?
是吧
Let's get to wash and sleep.
洗脸刷牙 睡觉
Still, I regret a bit.
还是有点后悔
I do not know why.
是怎么回事呢
Listen to me, Xin,
我跟你说 心心
Dad has talked for a long time.
爸说了半天
It doesn't matter who is right or wrong.
不管谁对 谁错
As the younger generation,
当晚辈的
you should
给长辈
apologize to the elders.
赔个不是
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
这不丢人
Didn't I just say
我刚才不是说了吗
that I had not hit Haowen?
我没打浩文
I didn't do it, why do I have to apologize?
没打浩文我道什么歉呀
Xin,
心心
why do you always get caught up in this?
你为什么老是纠结
It doesn't matter
你打还是没打
whether you hit him or not,
还是不故意碰的
or if it was an accident,
还是他磕的
or if he bumped into something.
这都不重要
So I must apologize no matter what.
就是错没错都要道歉呗
As a daughter-in-law, you should
你这当儿媳妇的
show some respect to your mother-in-law.
你就给婆婆一个面子
It is not a big deal?
又能咋的
Respect her?
我给她面子
Yet she came all the way here
她大老远的
to accuse me.
跑到我家来兴师问罪
She said that I'm lazy
说我懒 说我作
and troublesome,
说我闹
and that I'm never satisfied.
说我有什么不满足的
But I didn't argue with her.
但我没有跟她吵
With my temper,
我这个脾气
I didn't even argue with her.
我都没跟她吵
I said, "Mom,
我说 妈
this is between me and Haowen.
这是我跟我老贾
It's our personal issue.
我们两口子的事
Can you please stay out of it?"
您别管行吗
She said no.
不行
She kept pushing and pushing.
不依不饶地顶上去
It aroused my anger.
火就是到那儿了
And it couldn't be taken back.
收不回去了
Yes.
对
I think it's her mother who's wrong.
我觉得就是他妈不对
She didn't investigate thoroughly.
那你没有调查清楚
How could she
你为什么要
blame my daughter?
埋怨我姑娘呢
Exactly.
就是啊
Right?
对不对
This is completely wrong.
这太不对了
But don't forget,
可是你别忘喽啊
Haowen
老贾
lost his father when he was young.
从小就没了父亲
It was his Mom
是他妈
who raised him on her own.
一个人把他拉扯大的
His mother had a tough time.
他妈不容易吧
But I've been good to her, too.
那我对她也很好啊
I'm not saying you've been bad to her.
是我没说你对她不好
She can stay as long as she wants.
她想来住多久就住多久
She can live in the big villa.
大别墅给她住着
She can see her grandson
孙子她想怎么看
whenever she wants.
就怎么看
We can even send him to her.
给她送过去也行
She can watch him here as well.
在这儿看也行
Haven't I been nice enough?
我做 做得不好吗
Sometimes,
那有时候
why are you willing to apologize
为什么是你妈错了
to your Mom after she gets angry
你惹你妈生气完了之后
even if it's your mother's fault?
你能去道歉
But that's my real Mom.
那是亲妈
Can she and my mother-in-law be the same?
亲妈和婆婆她能一样吗
Why can't they be the same?
她怎么就不一样呢
Since you got married,
从你们结婚以后
I've treated Li Lin
我拿李临
and Haowen
我拿这个浩文
as if they were my own sons.
我一直当儿子
Yes,
是
I know.
我知道
It's natural for Haowen to spoil me.
那贾浩文宠我是应该的
As a couple,
我们两口子
we live our life
过两口子小日子
and have marital issues,
我们有夫妻情绪
isn't that normal?
那不是很正常吗
Why make a big deal about it?
为什么要上纲上线呢
What do you mean by saying that
什么叫他宠你
it's natural for him to spoil you?
就是应该的
As a daughter-in-law,
你当媳妇
can't you be more forgiving
就不能原谅原谅
and considerate towards your husband?
体贴体贴丈夫呢
Think about it honestly.
你摸着良心你想一想
Is it really you
是人
who's making trouble, or is it Haowen?
是你作还是老贾作
Isn't it always you
哪次不都是你
who comes back making a fuss?
叮铃咣啷地你回来
Isn't it my right?
我作不应该吗
The next day,
第二天不就
did he come to pick you up?
来接你来了吗
[Why should I act up?]
我为什么作
[Was it because of you?]
是不是你弄的
[Isn't it because you spoiled me?]
是不是你惯的
You've spoiled me until I'm thirty-four.
你惯我到三十四岁了
Now you won't let me act up?
不让我作了
Does that make sense?
有这道理吗
Then if you want Haowen to spoil you,
那你让老贾惯你
he needs some time.
得慢慢惯你啊
I've spoiled you for decades.
我惯了你几十年了
You've got married for only one decade.
你俩结婚才十 十多年
Yes, one decade.
十多年是啊
I've given birth to two children.
我给他生了两胎
Shouldn't he continue to spoil me?
他不得继续惯我吗
If he doesn't spoil me,
他不惯我
I wouldn't have this second child.
我还不生二胎了呢
[What's the problem?]
怎么了
Am I right?
莫名其妙
Well, you...
不是 你
You can't say that just because
你不能说
you're having the second child,
你怀了 二胎了
so no one can talk sense to you.
就不能跟你讲道理了
Who's being unreasonable?
谁不讲道理啊
I've done so much for
我给他们老贾
his family.
老贾家
Haven't I contributed enough?
做的贡献还不够多呀
Haven't I sacrificed enough?
我不够牺牲吗
I raised Xiongxiong until he is seven.
我把熊熊拉扯到七岁
I couldn't do anything at home.
我在家什么事都干不了
I'm a designer, Dad.
我也是设计师啊 爸爸
I have dreams, too.
我有梦想的
[The brand Dream Heart]
我跟老贾
[I created with Haowen]
创立的（梦心）品牌
[was named after me.]
是我的名字命名的
Now I've been staying home every day
我天天在家待着
to raise the kids. Is it easy for me?
我拉扯孩子我容易吗
Finally, Xiongxiong is seven.
好不容易熊熊七岁了
I wanted to start working again.
我想要出来工作
And now one more baby is on the way.
又来一个
Alright.
好
[I understand]
你刚才说的这些
[what you just said.]
爸都知道
[But let's put it this way,]
那么话又说回来
Haowen spends his whole day
老贾一天在 在外头
managing a big business.
操持那么一大一个场子
He might drink outside,
在外头一喝酒
getting drunk.
喝得烂醉了
Which man wants to
哪个男人愿意
get drunk outside?
在外头喝酒啊
please others outside?
愿意赔别人笑脸呢
With a wife and children to raise,
他有老婆 他有孩子
doesn't he have to go out
他不得出去
and work hard to earn money?
拼命地赚钱吗
[And he gives all the money to you,]
赚的钱不都给你了吗
[so you can live]
你才能过上
[the way you do now.]
现在这个日子吗
Shouldn't he earn money?
他赚钱不应该吗
[Why is it always]
怎么老是
[about you and your needs?]
你 你 你的呢
[Shouldn't he give me the money?]
他给我不应该吗
He started from scratch.
他白手起家的
When I was with him,
我跟他在一起的时候
he had nothing.
他屁都不是
So how did you get to where you are today?
那你为什么有今天呢
I worked hard with him and earned it.
我跟他摸爬滚打来的呀
Exactly.
对呀
Stop talking about you and your needs.
你别老说你 你的
I've been talking to you for so long,
跟你说了这么半天
but you're not listening.
你油盐不进呢你
What's wrong with you?
你怎么回事啊
Apologize.
道个歉
I didn't do anything wrong.
我没做错 让我道歉
Why should I apologize?
凭什么呀
Whatever you say is wrong.
你说什么都不对
Let me tell you,
我跟你讲
today
我今天
when I got home,
我回到家里
I just wanted some peace and quiet.
我就是想躲躲清静
But his mother came and we had a fight.
他妈来 我跟他妈闹
It's the issues between me and my husband,
我们两口子的事
I never mentioned divorce.
我根本没说离婚
You're so troublesome.
你太能作了你
How am I being troublesome?
我怎么作
His mother said it,
他妈说我作
and you said it, too.
你也说我作
I can't stay in this home anymore.
这个家没法待
I'll pack my things now.
我现在就去收拾东西
Don't be my father.
你别当我爸
Be Haowen's father instead.
你当老贾他爸去吧
Mom.
妈
Coming.
来了
Haowen is here.
浩文来了
I've been busy all along.
我刚一直在忙呢
I'm now picking up Xin.
接心心回家
Your dad is scolding her.
你爸正训她呢
It's all my mom's fault, saying nonsense.
都怪我妈瞎说
Mom,
妈
I apologize for my mother's temper.
我妈那脾气您别介意啊
We were handling things well.
我们小两口好好的
If she didn't interfere,
她不掺和
we would be fine.
我们一点事没有
I apologize on her behalf.
我替她给您道个歉
Xin is pregnant now,
心心现在怀孕
and her temper is bad.
她脾气暴
Please don't take it to heart.
你别往心里去才是
How can I?
我怎么会啊
I understand Xin well.
心心我还不了解
Xu Guanghua, I'm telling you...
许光华 我跟你说啊
Dad.
爸
Hurry!
快
What's going on?
咋回事啊这
Phone, Meng'an.
电话 梦安
It's Mengxin.
这梦心
What does she want now?
这干什么玩意儿 真是
Hello.
喂
What's wrong in the middle of the night?
你又怎么了大半夜的
[Meng'an]
姐
[Dad has passed out.]
咱爸晕倒了
[You need to come quickly, Meng'an.]
你快来啊 姐
Dad has passed out?
爸晕倒了
What happened?
爸怎么晕倒的